Guide to the Amos Niven Wilder and Wilder Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Isabel Wilder Papers, 1913–1994; Series V
  - Correspondence, 1913–1994
    - Partial name correspondence, 1950–1979
      - Bill, 1950, 1954 (Box 97, Folder 1213)
      - Bread Load Writers' Conference, 1935 (Box 97, Folder 1214)
      - Channing, Carol, 1980 (Box 97, Folder 1215)
      - Copyright application and Oxford Tennis Club tickets, 1922 (Box 97, Folder 1216)
      - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1935 (Box 97, Folder 1217)
      - D., Robert, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1218)
      - de Vargas, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1219)
      - Dick, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1220)
      - Doris and Arnold, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1221)
      - Elizabeth, 1959 (Box 97, Folder 1222)
      - Elsa, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 1223)
      - Evelyn, 1953–1958 (Box 97, Folder 1224)
      - "Everybody", "All of you" correspondence, 1953–1954 (Box 97, Folder 1225)
      - Fern, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1226)
      - Ffolkes, David, undated (Box 97, Folder 1227)
      - Francesco, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1228)
      - Glenway, 1957 (Box 97, Folder 1229)
      - Gracie and Alice, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1230)
      - Guelfo, 1953, 1958 (Box 97, Folder 1231)
      - Harold, 1946 (Box 97, Folder 1232)
      - Helen, 1958 (Box 97, Folder 1233)
      - Helen and Bob, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1234)
      - Henrietta, 1953 (Box 97, Folder 1235)
      - Hill, Eldon C., 1965 (Box 97, Folder 1236)
      - Iris, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 1237)
      - Jed, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1238)
      - Joan, 1954 (Box 97, Folder 1239)
      - John, 1956–1959 (Box 97, Folder 1240)
      - Kanin, Garson and Gordon, Ruth, 1950, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 1241-1242)
      - Miss Klausner, 1953 (Box 97, Folder 1243)
      - Larry, 1953 (Box 97, Folder 1244)
      - Leigh, Vivien, undated (Box 97, Folder 1245)
      - Lerner, Alan Jay, 1984 (Box 97, Folder 1246)
      - Lesser, Howard, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 1247)
      - Ling, Kong, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1248)
      - Louise, 1958–1960 (Box 97, Folder 1249)
      - Madison, Wisconsin photocopy, 1984 (Box 97, Folder 1250)
      - Marion, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1251)
      - Mary and Leslie, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1252)
      - Mickel, Liselotte, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 1253)
      - Mrs. Bradford, 1965 (Box 97, Folder 1254)
      - Miss Grindle, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1255)
      - Miss Stock, 1965 (Box 97, Folder 1256)
      - Monty, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 1257)
      - Mr. Naegeli, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1258)
      - Property inventory, copyright renewal claims and spare envelopes, circa 1950 (Box 97, Folder 1259)
      - Quintero, Jose B., 1976 (Box 97, Folder 1260)
      - Reed, Bertha Wilder, 1949 (Box 97, Folder 1261)
      - Rideout, W., 1977 (Box 97, Folder 1262)
      - Rosa, 1958 (Box 97, Folder 1263)
      - Ruth, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 1264)
      - Saralee, 1954–1957 (Box 97, Folder 1265)
      - State of Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1977 (Box 97, Folder 1266)
      - Susan, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1267)
      - Swan, Alfred, 1976 (Box 97, Folder 1268)
      - Terry, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1269)
      - Thompson, Daniel V., 1960–1979 (Box 98, Folder 1270-1272)
      - Titley, Mildred Squires, 1952 (Box 98, Folder 1273)
      - Todd, Margaret and Charles, undated (Box 98, Folder 1274)
      - Troxell, Janet, 1955–1958 (Box 98, Folder 1275)
      - Unidentified, 1953; undated (Box 98, Folder 1276-1277)
      - University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1984 (Box 98, Folder 1278)
      - Virginia, 1956 (Box 98, Folder 1279)
      - Virginia and Harold, 1956 (Box 98, Folder 1280)
      - Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters, 1978–1980 (Box 98, Folder 1282-1283)
      - Zaki, Mohamed Abdalla, 1977 (Box 98, Folder 1284)
      - Miss Zekowski and Mr. Berne, 1962 (Box 98, Folder 1285)
    - Isabel and Thornton Wilder related corrrespondence, 1959–1987
      - Channing, Carol, 1973–1986 (Box 99, Folder 1286)
        Includes correspondence from Carol Channing and Charles Lowe to Isabel as well as photcopied notes from Thornton Wilder.
      - Kerr, Chester correspondence, 1980–1983 (Box 99, Folder 1287)
        Includes correspondence from Chester Kerr of Ticknor and Fields mostly about Gilbert Harrison's The Enthusiast.
      - K correspondence, 1962–1987 (Box 99, Folder 1288)
      - Great Lakes Shakespeare Festival, 1984 (Box 99, Folder 1289)
        Includes correspondence relating to Wilder Weekend held in Cleveland, Ohio.
      - L correspondence, 1975–1977 (Box 99, Folder 1290)
      - Lavery, Emmet correspondence and photocopied articles, 1972–1980 (Box 99, Folder 1291-1292)
      - Lesser, Sol, 1978–1979 (Box 99, Folder 1293)
      - Lifton, Paul correspondence and writing, 1982 (Box 99, Folder 1294)
      - M correspondence, 1965–1980 (Box 99, Folder 1295)
      - Mitchell, Margaret correspondence and typed piece on the 6718 WAC Headquarters Platoon, 1980 (Box 99, Folder 1296)
      - N correspondence, 1975–1984 (Box 99, Folder 1297)
      - O correspondence, 1976–1978 (Box 99, Folder 1298)
      - Olley, Francis correspondence, 1977–1981 (Box 99, Folder 1299)
      - P correspondence, 1976–1977 (Box 99, Folder 1300)
      - Powers, Lyall H. correspondence, 1981 (Box 99, Folder 1301)
      - Quintero, Jose correspondence, 1975–1982 (Box 99, Folder 1302)
      - R correspondence, 1975–1980 (Box 99, Folder 1303)
      - Reich, John correspondence, 1986–1987 (Box 99, Folder 1304)
      - S correspondence, 1969–1982 (Box 99, Folder 1305-1306)
      - Sahl, Hans correspondence, 1971–1988 (Box 99, Folder 1307)
      - Seldes, Marian correspondence, 1979–1984 (Box 99, Folder 1308)
      - Sheean, Diana "Dinah" correspondence, 1977–1980 (Box 99, Folder 1309)
      - Smith, Linda correspondence, 1977–1979 (Box 99, Folder 1310)
      - Snider, Gerald correspondence, 1981–1982 (Box 99, Folder 1311)
      - Snow, Emma Folger correspondence and clippings, 1979–1982 (Box 99, Folder 1312)
      - Student general correspondence, 1970–1977 (Box 99, Folder 1313)
        Includes correspondence mostly from foreign students.
      - Swan, Alfred correspondence, 1977–1985 (Box 100, Folder 1314)
      - T correspondence, 1975–1978 (Box 100, Folder 1315)
      - Telegrams, condolence, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 1316)
        Condolences sent to Isabel Wilder after Thornton's death.
      - Talma, Louise correspondence and clippings, 1959–1985 (Box 100, Folder 1317-1318)
      - Unknown condolence correspondence, 1975–1977 (Box 100, Folder 1319)
        Labeled as unknown by Isabel Wilder.
      - V correspondence, 1976 (Box 100, Folder 1320)
      - W correspondence, 1972–1978 (Box 100, Folder 1321)
      - Walsh, Claudette correspondence, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 1322)
      - Williams, Mary Ellen correspondence, 1978 (Box 100, Folder 1323)
      - Williams, Michael V. correspondence, 1982 (Box 100, Folder 1324)
      - Wixson, Douglas correspondence, 1978–1979 (Box 100, Folder 1325)
      - Y correspondence, 1975–1976 (Box 100, Folder 1326)
    - Correspondence and materials related to Thornton Wilder, 1926–1992
      - Wilder, Thornton typescript correspondence copies to his parents, undated (Box 100, Folder 1327)
        Potential typed copies of letters written to Amos Parker and Isabella Wilder. Some are dated 1917 from Oberlin.
      - "Toddie" correspondence, 1968 (Box 100, Folder 1328)
      - "The Indian Head", 1960 (Box 100, Folder 1329)
        Includes a poem, "Homage", written by Amos Niven Wilder.
      - "Thanks Paradoxical", undated (Box 100, Folder 1330)
        A typescript poem attributed to Isabella Niven Wilder.
      - Freeman, Edward correspondence, 1969–1982 (Box 100, Folder 1331)
      - Wilder family research correspondence, 1962–1976 (Box 100, Folder 1332)
      - Wilder, Isabel and Dakin, Janet Wilder passports, 1927–1938 (Box 100, Folder 1333)
        Chiefly correspondence between Isabel and Amos Wilder with Edward and Harold Wilder.
      - Reese, William and Kitty correspondence, 1979–1991 (Box 100, Folder 1334)
      - Mt. Carmel cemetery materials, 1958–1992 (Box 100, Folder 1335)
        Includes headstone photographs, correspondence, and forms.
      - Diaries and fragments, 1928–1941 (Box 101, Folder 1336-1338)
      - The Thirtieth Bead script, undated (Box 101, Folder 1339)
        A play written by Isabel Wilder.
      - Up in a Villa and The Blessed Monster scripts, 1928; undated (Box 101, Folder 1340-1341)
        Both plays written by Isabel Wilder.
      - A Charmed Life, circa 1937 (Box 101, Folder 1342)
        A short story written by Isabel Wilder.
      - Alice Washburn materials, 1989–1990 (Box 101, Folder 1343)
        Correspondence and brochures relating to the Hamden Historical Society's celebration of Washburn's career.
      - "Drugs to Halt Damage after Head Injuries" clipping, undated (Box 101, Folder 1344)
      - Thornton Wilder at the Hamden Public Library materials (3 folders), 1975–1987 (Box 101, Folder 1345-1347)
      - Hamden Bicentennial Commission, 1975–1983 (Box 101, Folder 1348-1349)
      - Thornton Wilder Memorial correspondence and clippings (2 folders), 1979–1990 (Box 101, Folder 1350-1351)
      - Keane, Paul correspondence, 1975–1986 (Box 101, Folder 1352)
      - Samuel French Inc. correspondence and "About Thornton Wilder, The "Alcestiad", "The Drunken Sisters" and Notes Towards a Production" typescript photocopies, 1979–1990 (Box 101, Folder 1353)
      - The Skin of Our Teeth Harvard production correspondence, 1986 (Box 101, Folder 1354)
      - Harper and Row Publishers, Inc. correspondence, 1976–1980 (Box 102, Folder 1355-1356)
      - Fischer, Brigette correspondence and photocopied articles, 1956–1978 (Box 102, Folder 1357)
      - Canfield, Cass correspondence, 1975–1984 (Box 102, Folder 1358)
      - The Fulton-Cushing Collection of the Axion Research Foundation correspondence, 1991–1992 (Box 102, Folder 1359)
      - Robert A. Freedman Dramatic Agency and Harold Freedman Brandt & Brandt Dramatic Department correspondence, 1976–1985 (Box 102, Folder 1360)
      - The Thornton Wilder Writing Competition at the Hamden Public Library materials, 1989–1991 (Box 102, Folder 1361-1363)
        Includes correspondence, clippings, and writing submissions.
      - Longmans, Green & Co. correspondence, 1947 (Box 102, Folder 1364)
      - William Morris Agency correspondence, 1992 (Box 102, Folder 1365)
      - Written permissions correspondence, 1976–1991 (Box 102, Folder 1366)
      - Reader's Digest correspondence, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 1367)
      - Penguin Books correspondence, 1969–1980 (Box 102, Folder 1368)
      - Yale Gift and Alumni Association materials, 1978–1993 (Box 102, Folder 1369-1370)
        Also includes a decorative pin owned by Isabel Wilder.
      - Channel 13 correspondence, 1989 (Box 102, Folder 1371)
      - Women's Independent Film Exchange correspondence, 1985–1987 (Box 102, Folder 1372)
      - Yale Drama School Alumni files, 1926–1990 (Box 429, Folder 1373-1375)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Box 429: Restricted until 2053. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
      - Yale Film Study Center correspondence, 1985 (Box 102, Folder 1376)
        Correspondence concerning the acquisition of Mary Ellen Bute's papers.
      - Yale Co-op correspondence and clippings, 1985–1989 (Box 102, Folder 1377)
      - Medical visit summary, 1990 (Box 430, Folder 1378)
        Box 430: Restricted until January 1, 2066. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
      - The Journals of Thornton Wilder materials, 1985–1986 (Box 103, Folder 1379)
        Includes invoices, marketing reports, correspondence, and clippings.
      - Yale Music Library and School of Music materials, 1978–1989 (Box 103, Folder 1380)
        Includes correspondence and an issue of Nota Bene.
      - Richards, Lloyd correspondence and documents, 1983–1991 (Box 103, Folder 1381-1382)
      - Yale School of Drama Library correspondence and scholarship list, circa 1981 (Box 103, Folder 1383)
      - Yale University Library Gift correspondence, 1975–1992 (Box 103, Folder 1384-1385)
      - Yale Davenport College correspondence, 1976–1993 (Box 103, Folder 1386)
    - Isabel Wilder correspondence, 1936–1994
      - A correspondence, 1975–1983 (Box 103, Folder 1387)
      - Aikkola, Margaret correspondence and typescript writings, 1986–1987 (Box 103, Folder 1388)
      - The Skin of Our Teeth televised production clippings and correspondence, 1982–1986 (Box 103, Folder 1389)
        Also includes a Playbill from the 1986 Classic Stage Company production.
      - B correspondence, 1975–1981 (Box 103, Folder 1390)
        Includes a handwritten letter from Thornton Wilder addressed to Miriam (potentially Beer Hofmann Lens) dated July 29, 1975
      - Basquin, Kit correspondence and typescript writing, 1985–1988 (Box 103, Folder 1391)
        Includes Kit Basquin's piece entitled "Mary Ellen Bute's Film Adaptation of Finnegan's Wake".
      - Baumgarten, Alan E. correspondence, 1978–1979 (Box 103, Folder 1392)
      - Berlin, Jeffrey correspondence and photocopied articles, 1978–1982 (Box 103, Folder 1393)
        Includes multiple copies of "Richard Beer-Hofman and Theodor Reik: A Letter in Exile" from the The Psychoanalytic Review.
      - Brunauer, Dalma correspondence and typescript writing, 1976; undated (Box 103, Folder 1394)
        The enclosed piece is entitled "The Bridge is Love: An Interpretation of Wilder's The Bridge of San Luis Rey".
      - Burbank, Rex correspondence, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 1395)
      - C correspondence, 1975–1984 (Box 104, Folder 1396)
        Includes correspondence addressed to Thornton Wilder.
      - Carroll, Walter correspondence, 1976 (Box 104, Folder 1397)
      - Wilder, Thornton typed V-mail correspondence to family members, 1943–1944 (Box 104, Folder 1398)
        Addressed to "Dear Ones", his mother, and his sister, each letter is typed two to a page.
      - Circle in the Square correspondence, ticket to "Thornton Wilder", and program page, 1977–1985 (Box 104, Folder 1399)
      - Coley, Thomas correspondence and writings, 1979–1986 (Box 104, Folder 1400-1401)
      - Concord Players correspondence, clippings, and ephemera, 1985 (Box 104, Folder 1402)
      - D correspondence, 1940–1984 (Box 104, Folder 1403)
        Includes a letter addressed to Thornton Wilder and a clipping.
      - E correspondence, 1976 (Box 104, Folder 1404)
      - F correspondence, 1975–1983 (Box 104, Folder 1405)
      - Findley, Timothy, 1978–1981 (Box 104, Folder 1406)
      - G correspondence, 1975–1980 (Box 104, Folder 1407)
      - Gelber, Mark, 1982–1983 (Box 104, Folder 1408)
        Dr. Mark Gelber wrote to Isabel about the relationship between Thornton Wilder and Stefan Zweig.
      - Gilbert, Leatrice, 1976–1983 (Box 104, Folder 1409)
      - Goldstone, Richard correspondence and clippings, 1967–1977 (Box 104, Folder 1410)
      - Greene, Shirley and Waldo, 1976–1987 (Box 104, Folder 1411-1412)
      - H correspondence, 1974–1987 (Box 104, Folder 1413)
      - Haberman, Donald, 1977–1988 (Box 104, Folder 1414)
      - Harper and Row Publishers, Inc, 1977–1980 (Box 104, Folder 1415)
      - Harris, Julie, 1977–1978 (Box 105, Folder 1416)
      - Harrison, Gilbert A., 1977–1983 (Box 105, Folder 1417-1420)
        The second folder includes typed and photocopied correspondence written by Isabel and addressed to Gilbert.
      - Harrison, Gilbert A. legal correspondence, 1979 (Box 105, Folder 1421)
      - Harrison, Gilbert A. lists and clippings, 1978–1979 (Box 105, Folder 1422)
        Includes lists of photos as well as an author's query printed in news publications.
      - Harvard Theatre Collection, 1988 (Box 105, Folder 1423)
      - Horgan, Paul correspondence and writings, 1977–1987 (Box 105, Folder 1424-1425)
      - Horovitz, Israel correspondence and clipping, 1976 (Box 105, Folder 1426)
      - J correspondence and clipping, 1977 (Box 105, Folder 1427)
      - Jackson, Esther, 1978–1985 (Box 105, Folder 1428)
      - Toklas, Alice B., 1940–1957 (Box 105, Folder 1429)
      - Cowley, Malcolm, 1976–1980 (Box 105, Folder 1430)
      - Perlis, Vivian, 1986–1989 (Box 105, Folder 1431)
        Includes correspondence regarding correspondence between Thornton Wilder and Aaron Copland.
      - Benet, Laura, 1976–1979 (Box 105, Folder 1432)
      - Burns, Edward, 1975–1993 (Box 105, Folder 1433)
      - B correspondence, 1986; undated (Box 105, Folder 1434)
      - C correspondence, 1989 (Box 105, Folder 1435)
      - Chaliapin, Boris, 1953 (Box 105, Folder 1436)
      - Chapman, "Betsy" Mrs. Gilbert W., 1977 (Box 105, Folder 1437)
      - Clemens, Cyril correspondence, 1974–1978 (Box 105, Folder 1438)
      - Colfax, Sibyl, circa 1946 (Box 105, Folder 1439)
      - Anthill typescript history and photocopied "History of Dane County", undated (Box 105, Folder 1440)
      - Leibert, Herman W. correspondence and keepsake ephemera for his 75th birthday, 1976–1986 (Box 105, Folder 1441)
      - Aikkola, Margaret correspondence and "The Intent of the Author on Stage and Screen in Thornton Wilder's Our Town", 1987–1993 (Box 105, Folder 1442)
      - Ardrey, Helen correspondence and Ardrey family photographs, 1972–1990 (Box 106, Folder 1443-1444)
      - Dahlberg, Gilda correspondence, 1976–1977 (Box 106, Folder 1445)
      - De Rachewiltz, Mary, 1975 (Box 106, Folder 1446)
      - Downs, Arthur, 1977 (Box 106, Folder 1447)
      - Edel, Leon, 1977–1980 (Box 106, Folder 1448)
      - Fischer, Brigitte, 1977 (Box 106, Folder 1449)
      - Findley, Timothy and Matalon, Vivian, 1990–1991 (Box 106, Folder 1450)
        Also includes a copy of "Inside Memory".
      - G correspondence, 1978–1992 (Box 106, Folder 1451)
      - Gallup, Donald correspondence, clippings, and photocopied articles, 1952–1994 (Box 106, Folder 1452-1455)
      - Glenn, Leslie C., 1976 (Box 106, Folder 1456)
      - Haas, Robert B. correspondence, photocopied correspondence and articles, 1986; undated (Box 106, Folder 1457)
      - Haberman, Don, 1981–1994 (Box 106, Folder 1458)
      - Harrison, Gil, 1985–1992 (Box 106, Folder 1459)
      - Hayter, Augy correspondence and poetry, 1984; undated (Box 106, Folder 1460)
      - Hersey, John correspondence, clipping, and memorial service, 1976–1993 (Box 106, Folder 1461)
      - Horgan, Paul correspondence and ephemera, 1985–1991 (Box 106, Folder 1462)
      - Hotson, Leslie, 1960–1980 (Box 106, Folder 1463)
      - Hutchins, Robert Maynard correspondence, clippings, and memorial service program, 1933–1977 (Box 106, Folder 1464)
      - Jackson, Esther, 1985 (Box 106, Folder 1465)
      - K correspondence, 1940–1994 (Box 106, Folder 1466)
      - Kirkpatrick, Ralph correspondence, clippings, and ephemera, 1977–1984 (Box 106, Folder 1467)
      - L correspondence, 1944–1992 (Box 107, Folder 1468-1469)
      - "L., Malu", 1946 (Box 107, Folder 1470)
        Includes a letter addressed to Isabel from Thornton's former student.
      - Lane, Rose Wilder, 1936 (Box 107, Folder 1471)
      - Langford, Christine, 1941–1975 (Box 107, Folder 1472)
      - La Follette, Robert M. clippings, photocopied articles, and literature review, 1953; undated (Box 107, Folder 1473)
      - Laserna, Mario and Liliana, 1976–1993 (Box 107, Folder 1474)
      - Laughlin, James, 1977–1983 (Box 107, Folder 1475)
      - Lewis, Wilmarth Sheldon, 1976–1977 (Box 107, Folder 1476, Box 108 (Oversize), Folder 1491)
      - Picturesque Oxford, 1926 (Box 107, Folder 1477)
      - Botnick, Diane care of Isamu Noguchi correspondence, 1979 (Box 107, Folder 1478)
      - M correspondence, 1953; undated (Box 107, Folder 1479)
      - Mahler, Alma Werfel, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 1480)
      - Marias, Julian, 1975 (Box 107, Folder 1481)
      - Marquand, John, 1969 (Box 107, Folder 1482)
      - Mackaye, Percy's The Scarecrow program, 1975 (Box 107, Folder 1483)
      - McAfee, Helen, 1950–1951 (Box 107, Folder 1484)
      - O correspondence, 1978, 1993 (Box 107, Folder 1485)
      - Olson, Elder correspondence and photocopied writings, 1985–1988 (Box 107, Folder 1486)
      - Osborn, Robert and Elodie, 1972–1992 (Box 107, Folder 1487-1490)
      - P correspondence, 1986–1990 (Box 109, Folder 1493)
      - Partridge, Eric correspondence, clippings, and printed Christmas and New Year's Greetings, 1959–1977 (Box 109, Folder 1494)
      - Poland, Nancy, 1981–1985 (Box 109, Folder 1495)
      - Preminger, Marion Mill correspondence and photographs, 1953–1989 (Box 109, Folder 1496)
        Includes photographs of Albert Schweitzer.
      - R correspondence, 1932–1994 (Box 109, Folder 1497)
        Includes a letter from Faith Rockefeller.
      - Redlich, Herta Glaz, 1959–1982 (Box 109, Folder 1498)
      - S correspondence, 1988; undated (Box 109, Folder 1499)
      - Simonds, Bruce correspondence and ephemera, 1977–1985; undated (Box 109, Folder 1500)
      - Stahl, Hans, 1974–1989 (Box 109, Folder 1501)
      - Stein, Gertrude third party correspondence and ephemera, 1954–1986 (Box 109, Folder 1502)
        Also includes a nitrate negative, handwritten poetry, and a printed article.
      - Talma, Louise, 1938–1994 (Box 109, Folder 1503)
      - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1954 (Box 109, Folder 1504)
      - Troubetzkoy, Dorothy Ulrich correspondence, typescript poetry, and ephemera, 1940–1993 (Box 109, Folder 1505-1506)
      - Troxell, Janet and Gilbert Camp correspondence and clipping, 1954–1979 (Box 109, Folder 1507)
      - W correspondence, 1943–1987 (Box 109, Folder 1508)
      - Walsh, Claudette, 1986–1994 (Box 109, Folder 1509)
      - Wescott, Glenway, 1950–1976 (Box 109, Folder 1510)
      - Woollcott, Alexander correspondence and "Five Thousand Letters to Alexander Woollcut", 1938–1984 (Box 109, Folder 1511)
      - Worth, Irene correspondence and photograph with Thornton Wilder, 1960–1989 (Box 109, Folder 1512)
    - General Isabel Wilder correspondence, 1922–1997
      - A correspondence, 1986–1990 (Box 110, Folder 1513)
      - Abatello family, 1992–1993 (Box 110, Folder 1514)
      - Adair, Bob and Ellie, 1989–1993 (Box 110, Folder 1515)
      - Allen, Mary, 1988–1993 (Box 110, Folder 1516)
      - Altbaum, Max and Caren, 1986–1994 (Box 110, Folder 1517)
      - Anglim, Philip, undated (Box 110, Folder 1518)
        Letter concerning Herschel Williams.
      - B correspondence, 1983–1994 (Box 110, Folder 1519)
      - C correspondence, 1982–1994 (Box 110, Folder 1520)
      - Clinchy, Everett R., 1979–1983 (Box 110, Folder 1521)
      - Consiglio family, 1989–1992 (Box 110, Folder 1522)
      - D correspondence, 1953–1991 (Box 110, Folder 1523)
      - Davidson, Louise, 1964–1993 (Box 110, Folder 1524)
      - Durocher Associates photocopied analysis, undated (Box 110, Folder 1525)
      - Dwight, Sally, 1988–1993 (Box 110, Folder 1526)
      - Emeny, Brooks, 1936–1977 (Box 110, Folder 1527)
      - Ely, Harriet Jackson, 1922–1994 (Box 110, Folder 1528)
      - Evans, Bradford and Dot, 1984–1994 (Box 110, Folder 1529)
      - F correspondence, 1938–1994 (Box 111, Folder 1530)
      - Fisher, Juliana Scham correspondence, 1988–1994 (Box 111, Folder 1531)
      - Foster, Joe, 1991–1994 (Box 111, Folder 1532-1533)
      - Frulla, Guelfo, 1976–1993 (Box 111, Folder 1534)
      - G correspondence, 1989 (Box 111, Folder 1535)
      - Greene, Waldo, 1990–1992 (Box 111, Folder 1536)
      - H correspondence, 1979–1992 (Box 111, Folder 1537)
      - Haverly, John, 1960–1994 (Box 111, Folder 1538)
      - Heyde, Gary, 1975–1991 (Box 111, Folder 1539-1540)
      - Helga-Henriette Hufnagel, 1988–1992 (Box 111, Folder 1541)
      - I correspondence, 1931 (Box 111, Folder 1542)
      - M correspondence, 1989 (Box 112, Folder 1543)
      - R correspondence, 1986 (Box 112, Folder 1544)
      - S correspondence, 1939–1993 (Box 112, Folder 1545)
      - T correspondence, 1960–1993 (Box 112, Folder 1546)